再见了  专门装电池和外卖菜单的抽屉
Aww, goodbye, drawer dedicated to batteries and takeout menus.
再见了  墙上的凹痕
And goodbye, wall dent,
当年我们以为莉莉是长号神童时搞出来的
from when we thought Lily was a trombone prodigy.
米奇尔
Mitchell!
刚刚是你在这房子里最后一次翻白眼了
That was your last eye roll in this house!
话说  等二宝来到这个家以后
You know what, when the new baby comes,
你能别再这么频繁地翻白眼了吗
can you not do it as much?
因为  你以前经常在莉莉身边翻白眼  导致...
Because, you know, you did it around Lily a lot, and...
好吧  别别别  别把那个扔了
Okay... hey, hey, no, no, no. Don't throw those away.
我或许要用这个
I-I might want to use those
在全家人面前揭示二宝的到来
for my big baby reveal to the family.
如果他胆子够大  我可以玩埃尔顿·约翰逊那一套
If he's bald, I can do a whole Elton John thing.
我们不仅要搬家
Not only are we moving,
两周后我们还要再领养一个孩子
but we're adopting a baby that's due in two weeks.
那真是让我压力山大  因为11年前
And that is stressing me out because eleven years ago,
我配著《狮子王》的歌曲揭示了莉莉的到来
I revealed Lily with "The Lion King,"
真的压力很大
and there's a lot of pressure...
-自找的  -毕竟要超越自我太难了
- Self-imposed. - ...to top myself.
所以  我研究了几套方案
So, I've been workshopping a few ideas.
希望在座的各位都喜欢...
I hope everyone here likes...
宝宝
baby!
我可以预见这让大家惊呆了  对吧
I can see that taking everyone's breath away, no?
我更担心的是相关当局会把孩子没收回去
Uh, I'm more concerned about the city taking our baby away.
好了  修理工五分钟后就到
Okay, the repair guys are gonna be here in five minutes.
真不敢相信我会说这话
I can't believe I'm saying this,
但我们或许真能躲过罪...
but we might actually be getting away with...
你们怎么回来了
What are you guys doing home?
就是啊  你们不是去参加海滩清理活动了吗
Yeah, I thought you went to that beach cleanup.
我们尝试了  但那些在海滩上做瑜伽的人
Well, we tried, but the beach yoga people
连往别处挪一百英尺都不肯
wouldn't even move a hundred feet down.
还以为瑜伽人很能"灵活"变通呢
You'd think they'd have been a little more flexible.
菲尔
Oh, Phil.
好消息是  我们现在到家啦
The good news is, we're back and we are here
可以帮你们置办双胞胎的复活节派对了
to help you set up for the twins' Easter party.
我们可以的
Um, we're good.
我们完全可以应付
Anyway, we got this covered.
你们今天早上已经很劳累了
And you guys had such a long morning,
不如阿嬷阿公去小睡一会儿吧
why don't Gamma and Grampy grab a nap
这样就能精神满满地参加派对了  好吗
so that they're fresh for the party, huh?
好啦
Okay.
好吧
但我...
But I...
一切都好  我们可以的
It's all good. We got it.
上周末  爸爸妈妈
Last weekend, Mom and Dad
去蒙特雷参加菜蓟节去了
went to the artichoke festival in Monterey.
迪兰的妈妈请缨带双胞胎
And Dylan's mom had the twins,
于是我们就趁机办了个派对
so we took the opportunity to have a little party,
就为了看看我们是否还有那个疯劲儿
just to see if we still had it in us.
果然宝刀未老
We did.
我在追踪披萨外卖哥的动态
I'm trackin' the pizza guy,
披萨外卖哥  披萨外卖哥
the pizza guy, the pizza guy!
他叫易卜拉欣
His name is Ibrahim!
别忘了带蒜香面包结  蒜香面包结
Don't forget the garlic knots, garlic knots, garlic knots!
哟  这派对真是"史棒"
Yo! This party is the GOAT.
就是"有史以来最棒的派对"
Greatest of all time.
我叫道格  是住你们家街对面的邻居
I'm Doug, your across-the-street neighbor.
我正好在倒垃圾  听到派对的声音
I was just curbin' my bins, heard the party noise,
就想著来加入你们
thought I'd join up.
要给你加点酒吗
Want a refill on that?
我是绝对不会接受你的酒的
There is no scenario where I accept a drink from you.
酷
Lit.
看到邓菲家的人还能嗨起来  我心甚慰
Nice to see the Dunphy name still carries some party clout.
话说  丛林果汁快没了
You know, we're running low on jungle juice.
用毛巾吸起来  再拧到你的杯子里去吧
Just soak it up with a towel and wring it back into your cup.
好吧
Okay.
好酷
Cool!
这是什么品种的
What kind is that?
今晚就不能有个人跟我好好聊聊天
Can I have one conversation tonight
别只知道打听我的蛇吗
without someone asking me about my snake?
老天啊
Good Lord!
-发生什么事了  -我踩在你洒的饮料上滑倒了
- What happened?! - I slipped on that drink you spilled.
脚踝伤得好重
Hurt my ankle really bad.
我不想告你
I mean, I don't want to sue you,
但我觉得也没有其他办法
but I don't really see any other option.
你觉得呢
Do you?
于是现在我给道格打工了
So now I work for Doug.
大家好啊
Hey, everybody!
易卜拉欣来了  他来了他来了
Ibrahim has arrived, has a...
别光盯著看  快灭火啊
Don't stare at it! Put it out!
我们暂时补救了一下
We made some temporary fixes
然后预约了修理工今天过来修
and scheduled repairs for today,
爸妈明明说好了这个时间他们会在海滩
when Mom and Dad said they'd be at the beach.
然后他们竟然提前回来了
Then they came home early.
无法信任自己的家人  人生真的太艰难了
It's just hard when you can't trust family members.
"阿嬷阿公一定很想小睡一会儿吧"
"Don't Gamma and Grampy want to take a nap?"
你不觉得这很侮辱人吗
That's not insulting to you?
菲尔
Phil.
-菲尔  -我...我没睡  我听著呢
- Phil! - I... wasn't sleeping. I was listening.
你真厉害  那可真是...
And g-good for you. That is...
一天之内走了好多步啊
That is a lot of steps for one day.
我在说孩子们
I was talking about the kids.
他们还真把我们当成七老八十的外公外婆对待了
They're treating us like actual grandparents
而非  那种...
instead of the... the...
风华正茂  过早抱上外孙的外公外婆
premature grandparents we clearly are.
我是我们水上有氧运动班里
I'm the only one in my aqua aerobics class
唯一不需要两根浮条的人
who doesn't need two noodles.
我把鸡蛋放进了一个可爱的篮子里
I put the eggs in a cute basket
为复活节寻彩蛋活动做准备
for the Easter egg hunt.
-我在杂志上看到的  -真萌
- I saw it in a magazine. - Cute.
-海莉  -不好
- Haley. - Oh, no.
亲爱的  你爸和我不想睡觉
Honey, your dad and I didn't feel like taking a nap.
不如你安排点派对的准备工作给我们吧
Why don't you give us a job for the party?
我们需要人来帮忙将蛋染色
Uh, well, we could use some help dyeing these eggs.
不过  不如你们先为派对换好衣服吧
But why don't you change for the party first?
-好主意  -太好了
- Oh, good idea! - Yes!
菲尔  快醒醒
Phil, wakey, wakey!
我们只有60秒  各位
Okay, we got sixty seconds, people.
动作必须快点  快
We gotta move fast. Come on. Come on.
快  快  快  快
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on, come on!
没错  就这样  快  快
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
快  快  快
Come on, move faster!
速度  速度  速度
Let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go!
你们能快点吗
Would you hurry it up a little bit?
快  赶紧离开  快  快  快走
Oh, come on! Get out of here now! Go, go, go!
非常感谢  我太爱你们了  再见
Thank you so much. I love you guys so much. Bye!
好了  我觉得我们成功逃脱了
Okay. I think we actually got away with it.
-不要啊  -我一说这话就大事不妙
- Oh, no. - I have to stop saying that.
派对上那家伙说他的蟒蛇怀孕了
That dude from the party said that his python was pregnant.
你觉得这有没有可能是蛇蛋
Do you think those could be her eggs?
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
是不是有一只快孵化了
Is one of them hatching?
真是太恶心了
That's so disgusting!
我们只能取消复活节派对了
We have to cancel the party!
什么  不可能
What? No way!
我们才刚跟那帮家长修复关系
We just got back in with this parent group
毕竟我们家女儿胡乱咬人
after our daughter's biting spree.
如果他们不喜欢自家孩子被可爱的幼儿轻咬
If they didn't love their kids being gummed by an adorable toddler,
我觉得他们也不会喜欢
I don't think they're gonna love
自家孩子被一条蟒蛇咬穿
their kids getting punctured by a python!
冷静
Calm down.
蛇只会把蛋都产在一个黑暗的地方
Snakes lay all their eggs in one dark place.
我已经全拿出来了  我这就送到宠物店去
I've got them all here. I'm gonna run them by the pet store.
天  其中一个在动吗  快拿走
Oh, my God. Is one of them moving? Get them out of here.
真是太恶心了  恶心  恶心  恶心
They're so gross. Gross, gross, gross, gross.
嘿  你这是要跑到哪儿去啊  小家伙
Hey, where you running off to, little buddy?
你又想跑到哪儿去啊  大家伙
And where are you running off to, big buddy?
你好啊  陌生人
Hey, stranger!
又要出门吗  我最近几乎都见不著你
Going out again? I barely see you these days.
我也想跟你一起玩  杰
I'd love to hang out, Jay,
但我要参加红酒俱乐部的聚会
but I've got a wine club meeting.
你喜欢红酒吗  我超爱红酒的
What, are you into wine? I love wine!
-好吧  回头见  -等等
- Okay. See ya. - Wait a minute!
我等会儿就开瓶红酒
I'm gonna open a bottle later on.
不如你带一瓶回来  我们一起品品酒
Why don't you bring one and we'll have a little tasting?
这主意还不赖
I guess I wouldn't mind that.
我回来时去趟商店
I'll stop by the store on my way back.
既然都去了  顺便发个慈悲帮我买瓶汽水吧
While you're there, would you be a prince and pick me up a soda?
我得跟功课奋战
I've got homework.
你哪来的五十大钞
Where'd you get a fifty?
不劳你费心
Don't worry about it.
欢迎来到你们的新家
Welcome to your new house!
我不记得这房间这么冷冰冰没人味啊
I don't remember this room feeling so stark and cold.
幸好这是智能房子
Luckily this is a smart house.
亚当  暖光模式
Adam, warm light mode.
已启动
Initiating.
不  不好
Oh, no... no!
不  这样只让窗边的霉菌更显眼了
No, that just brings out the molding around the windows.
这里是不是有点像养老院啊
I... Does it feel like we're in a nursing home?
亚当  派对模式
Adam, party mode!
已启动
Initiating.
天啊  不  这更糟了
Oh, God. No! No, that's... that's even worse.
我...  抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry, I just...
我就是觉得自己好像没来过一样
I don't feel like I've ever been in this house before.
亚当  我警告你[我对天发誓]
Adam, I swear to God!
已启动
Initiating.
我们是不是犯了个大错
Did we just make a huge mistake?
米奇尔  你知道你讨厌改变啊
Mitchell, you know you hate change.
还记得你剃光胡子那次吗
Remember when you shaved your beard?
你对著镜子尖叫  "老天  你丑绝人寰"
You screamed in the mirror, "Oh, my God, you look hideous!"
那是你好不好
That was you.
你今天一整天都抱怨个不停
I mean, you have been a crab all day long.
你怎么知道的  你都没跟我们在一起
How do you know? You haven't even been around us!
我照你尿性猜的
I took a crazy guess.
听著  这是买家的懊悔情绪
Look, this is buyer's remorse.
我从我的导师菲尔·邓菲那学到的
I learned that from my mentor, Phil Dunphy,
我知道如何能解决
and I know how to fix it.
跟我来  如果你还想活...
Come with me if you want to live...
在这栋房子里  并且不想当个扫兴鬼
in this house... and not be a bummer to everyone.
莉莉  你得帮我开始拆箱了
Lily, you need to help me start unpacking.
我们需要继续谋划二宝的盛大揭示
We need to work on my baby reveal.
亚当  思考模式
Adam, thinking mode.
已启动
Initiating.
我知道这听起来很疯  但真有用的
I know it sounds crazy, but it works.
为了接受新房子
In order to accept the new house,
你必须跟原来的家好好告别
you have to properly say goodbye to this place.
我才不要对著一栋房子说话呢
Okay, I'm not talking to a house. Okay?
还有  搬家工人为什么坐在外面不干活
And... And why are the movers just sitting out there?
别担心  我会搞定他们
Don't worry about them. I'll handle them.
我以前也当过搬家工人
I used to be a mover.
我帮前男友偷他兄弟的冰箱时
I kind of fell into it when I helped an ex-boyfriend
自然而然就进入了这一行
steal his brother's refrigerator.
等等  所以你当过出租车司机  美发师
Okay, wait, so you've been a cab driver, a hairdresser,
代言模特  还当过搬家工人
a spokesmodel, and a mover.
你的人生是真实的吗
I-Is your life real?
世上有什么是真实的吗
Is anything real?
我当哲学教授时
That was a question that I asked myself
时常问自己这个问题
when I was a philosophy professor.
好了  跟这房子道别吧
Now, say goodbye to the house.
告诉它它对你的意义
Tell it how much it meant to you.
对彼此坦诚说出真心话  就像两个
Be honest with each other, like two lovers
知道终于要分道扬镳的爱人一样
that know that the time has come when they must part ways.
好吧  通常我就只是
Okay, well, usually, I would just
把我的健身房会员卡从他钥匙扣上摘下来
take my gym membership off his keychain
然后把他介绍给我妈认识
and then introduce him to my mother.
你好  小房
Hey, house.
你们这些懒鬼
Hey, you humps!
我们是按小时付你们费的
We're paying you by the hour!
我们正休息喝咖啡  女士
We're on a coffee break, lady.
别给我来这套
Oh, don't give me that.
我以前也是干这行的
I used to do your job.
就是你们这种态度  让大家讨厌搬家工人
And this attitude, this is why people hate movers.
以及偷东西的恶习
That and all the stealing.
太过分了  你以为你能做得更好吗
Whoa! You think you can do better?
我也不想戳破你的"泡泡膜"
I hate to burst your bubble wrap,
但老娘知道我能
but I know I can.
其实我们今天还预约了另一家  这样正好了
We actually double booked today, so this works out.
-你自己搬吧  -不不不  等等
- Have at it. - Oh, no, no, no, no! Ay, wait!
回来啊  懒鬼
Come back, humps!
你怎么在摧残猫
What are you doing with the cat?
别担心嘛  到那天
Okay, don't worry. On the day,
我会用宝宝换掉拉里的
I will replace Larry with the baby.
等全家都围著桌子坐好
Once the family is all seated around the table,
我就解开安全绳
I'll undo the security rope
然后让宝宝在桌子上方飘过
and then let the baby hover above the table
让所有家人为之惊叹
for all the family to marvel at.
等等  电话响了
Wait. Phone's ringing.
喂
Hello?
是我
Yes, speaking.
什么
What?
不
No!
老公  你刚才是喝到了洗笔水吗
Oh, honey, did you just take a sip from the paintbrush water?
如果喝错了我会知道的啦  克莱尔
I think I'd know if I did, Claire.
这一定就是祖父母坐的老人桌吧
Oh! This must be the grandparents' table!
-话不能这么说  -不  我觉得不是
- I wouldn't say that. - No, I d... I don't think...
这两位是宝宝们的外祖父母  阿嬷阿公
These are the kids' grandparents, Gamma and Grampy.
很高兴认识你们呀
Oh, nice to meet you.
我是姥姥  这是姥爷
I'm Meemaw. This is Bobo.
你们见过嬷嬷和爷爷了吗
Have you met GimGim and Mimsy?
不如你们坐我们的位子吧
Oh, you know what? Why don't you take our seats?
我们好像坐错桌子了
I think we're at the wrong table.
我的背
Oh! My back!
我也常闪到腰
Oh, it happens to me all the time.
我来告诉你这种老人鞋的牌子名
I'm gonna get you the name of these shoes.
道格  我已经替你做过饭
Doug, I have cooked for you,
帮你喷过美黑喷雾
spray tanned you,
还帮你代过两次转招牌的班
taken two of your sign spinning shifts.
我还没赎完罪吗
Are we seriously not even yet?
你把这事看得太严重了
I think you're making too big a deal about this.
我只是需要你穿上小丑女的变装服
I just need you to dress up like Harley Quinn
然后给我游戏之夜的赢家做脚底按摩而已
and give a foot massage to the winner of my game night.
别担心
Don't worry.
赢的会是我
I'm gonna win.
听著  杰拉德又摔倒了
And get this, Gerald fell again.
这次摔断了手腕
Wrist this time.
那老头体内的钢钉[针]比裁缝含在嘴里的还多
That man's got more pins in him than a tailor's mouth.
他就是不肯学正确的摔倒姿势
He never learned how to fall the right way.
-自尊心太强了  -等等  摔跤还有正确姿势的吗
- Too proud. - Wait, there's a right way to fall?
你不是吧  还搭话
Really? A follow-up?
要抵抗住用手撑地阻止摔势的诱惑
Resist the temptation to break the fall with the hands.
改用屁屁著地
Land on your bottom.
摔肉无妨  摔骨则断
Aim for the meat, not the bone.
嬷嬷
Oh... Mimsy!
看见没  毫发无伤
See? Good as new.
我亲爱的老公  真是个绅士
My dear husband, such a gentleman.
他每次都帮我开浴缸门
He always opens the bathtub door for me.
知道了  我们先失陪一下
Yeah. Would you excuse us just a second?
因为她就是啊
'Cause she was.
这样真不好
It's not good.
就是说啊
Oh, totally!
我们就是在聊上次去蛙镇
We're just remembering something that happened
喝遍了每家酒吧的尼格罗尼鸡尾酒
on our last Negroni crawl in Frogtown.
蛙镇啊
Oh, Frogtown!
-"鸟骑著鸟"  -"鸟骑著鸟"
- Oh, "Bird on a bird!" - "Bird on a bird!"
你们都收到短视频博主布丽吉特
Oh, you all got the TikTok invite
发的抖音邀请了吧  她周四要开
Bridget from Quibi sent out for her matcha pop-up
抹茶快闪店
on Thursday, right?
-你们去吗  -当然  那听起来很...
- You guys down? - Oh, yeah, that sounds...
冰凉凉
frosty.
出了点小麻烦
Small hiccup.
我到宠物店时  发现少了一枚蟒蛇蛋
When I got to the pet store, I was down one python egg,
-也就是说...  -还有一枚在这里
- which means... - There's one still here.
没错  我找过客厅了  不在那里
Yeah, and I just checked the living room, and it's not there.
好了  小朋友们  都到外面去
Okay, nuggets! Everyone outside!
找彩蛋时间到啦
It's time for the egg hunt!
出了点小麻烦
Hey. Small hiccup.
轮到品尝我带来的这瓶酒啦
Now it's time for the bottle I brought.
用干净的杯子
Fresh glasses.
朋友  这瓶酒是2009年卓龙酒庄的好酒
This, my friend, is a 2009 Chateau Trotanoy.
最好把你的裤腰带系紧了
You might want to cinch your belt up.
他会让你爽到裤子炸掉
It's liable to blow your trousers off.
-还不错  -"不错"吗
- It's nice. - "Nice"?
我能懂你为什么会喜欢这款
I understand why you would like it,
但...  这种酒是我红酒俱乐部朋友们
but... this is what my wine club friends
会称为"网红爆款"的酒
would call "An obvious choice."
我懂  你还没长出品尝上等美酒的味蕾
I get it. You haven't developed a taste for fine wine yet.
我不想对你说这话
Um, I hate to say it,
但我应该比你多懂酒许多
but I probably know more about wine than you do.
两个月前  你喝个桃红葡萄酒
Two months ago, you couldn't drink rose
都还得混果汁才能喝下去
unless it was mixed with Snapple.
这件事只有一个办法可以分出高下了
There's only one way to settle this...
敢不敢来一场盲测品酒
are you up for a little blind taste test?
放马过来
Bring it.
乔  去酒窖选出5瓶随机的红酒
Joe, go to the wine cellar, pick out five random bottles.
-我们家有酒窖吗  -什么是酒窖
- We have a wine cellar? - What's a wine cellar?
你是我的第一个
You were my first.
我们一起经历了那么多
And we'd both been through so much.
我曾是个神经兮兮的人
I mean, I was neurotic.
你是栋浴室连接厨房的怪房子
You had a-a bathroom off the kitchen.
但我们找到了对方
But we both found each other.
总之我...
Anyway, I...
我觉得  我必须说些什么
I-I-I feel like, um, I have to say something.
不是你的错  都怪我
It's not you. It's... It's me.
我就是...
I just, um...
需要更多空间
I need more space.
但我们还是能记住旧日的美好时光啊
But we could still remember the good times.
比如我们刚搬进来时
Um, like... like when I first moved in
我全副家当只有那个音箱
and all I had was that boombox.
你觉得这样好不好
Yeah, um... what do you say? Yeah.
我们重温旧梦
One more time?
? 现在我有过最美好的时光 ?
♪ Now I've had the time of my life ♪
? 不  这是我从未有过的体验 ?
♪ No, I never felt like this before ♪
? 是的  我发誓这是实话 ?
♪ Yes, I swear it's the truth ♪
你觉得如何
What do you say? Huh?
是不是一下又回到了过去
Takes you right back, right?
那年情人节  也就是是2003
To Valentine's Day 2003...
and four.
? 这一切都是我欠你的 ?
♪ And I owe it all to you ♪
歌洛莉亚说得没错
Gloria was right.
在我做了告别后  我真的能接受新房子
Once I said goodbye, I was able to embrace this new house
然后接下来几周就能布置好它来迎接新宝宝
and spend the next few weeks getting ready for the baby.
我只是需要一个告别
I just needed closure.
还有...  那套衣服也该告别了
And... And s... And so did the drapes.
因为舞后来变得有点...  脏[辣]
Because the... the dancing got, uh... g-got pretty dirty.
? 因为我有了最美好的时光 ?
♪ Because I've had the time of my life ♪
? 不  这是我从未有过的体验 ?
♪ No, I never felt this way before ♪
? 是的  我发誓这是实话 ?
♪ Yes, I swear it's the truth ♪
? 这一切都是我欠你的 ?
♪ And I owe it all to you ♪
米奇尔
Mitchell!
宝宝提早到了
The baby's here. He's early.
什么  我还没准备好呢
What? I-I'm not ready!
那你赶紧准备好吧
Well, get ready.
我们之后还得谈谈为什么
And we will be discussing why you were
你背著我偷偷玩"最美好的时光"
"Time-of-my-Life-ing" without me.
菜鸟的味蕾会把这个认成赤霞珠
The uneducated palate would identify this as a Cabernet,
但其实呢  这是波尔多产的梅洛
when, in fact, it is a Merlot from Bordeaux.
-正确  -让你蒙中了
- Correct. - Oh! Lucky guess.
在我20多岁时  我跟一个
In my twenties, I befriended
来自巴黎的品酒师成为朋友  他叫马塞尔·卡洛
a sommelier from Paris... Marcel Caron.
其实我还去他那里住过
In fact, I went to stay with him.
我们彻夜饮酒直到睡去
We'd drink wine all night and fall asleep
耳边伴著蒙帕纳斯大街上的手风琴声
to the sound of an accordion on the Rue de Montparnasse.
这故事跟这瓶酒一样  水果味的"基"调太浓
Much like this wine, that story has too many fruity notes.
下一杯
Next glass.
请...  尝
And... sip.
这瓶是陈年的纳帕谷霞多丽
That is a mature Napa Valley Cabernet.
-正确  -吃灰吧  老头
- Correct. - Unh! Eat that, old man!
你其实可以不用每答对一题
You know, you don't have to spike the football
就要绕场一周耍帅的
every time you get an answer right.
全天下只有你可以把聊酒
Only you could make talking about wine
搞得装逼味那么浓
into something obnoxious.
比数平手  2比2
Score is tied, two-two.
是时候来品尝最后一杯酒了
Time now for the final wine.
请开始答题
And to reveal the answer...
等等
Wait a minute.
或许我们不应该亮答案
Maybe we shouldn't.
在我们把这事变成比赛之前
Before we turned this into a competition,
本来都喝得挺开心不是吗
we were both having fun, right?
我们在做一件咱俩都喜欢的事
We were doing something we both liked.
我是有发现今天这一下午
It did occur to me that this whole afternoon,
我们俩没人去看时间
neither one of us checked our watch once.
如果我们亮了答案  有一个人就要不好受
And if we flip this over, one of us is gonna feel bad
到时候这件事就变没意思了
and it could ruin the thing.
面对现实吧  我们父子也没多少共同话题
I mean, let's face it, we don't have a ton in common,
但今天我在你身上看到了一点自己的影子
but today I saw a little bit of me in you.
你跟人比输赢时也可以很没品
You can be a competitive jerk.
听你去巴黎度过夏天的故事后
And based on that summer in Paris story,
我发现你也有敏感细腻甚至如香水般...
you can be kind of a sensitive, even perfumy type of...
够了
That'll do.
当你从你的旅行回来后
Look, when you get back from your trip,
我们把品酒这事变成固定活动吧
why don't we make this a thing?
我们可以每个月一起品酒一次
We'll have a wine tasting once a month...
不比赛  纯品
without the competition.
我加入
I'm in.
妈的
Damn it!
计较输赢的小混蛋
Competitive bastard.
真是爱死这小子了
Oh, I love that kid.
面对现实吧  亲爱的
Time to face facts, honey.
这是给我们坐的老人桌
It's the grandparent's table for us.
菲尔外公是吧
Grandpa Phil, huh?
我是也不介意以后学老人在健身房裸身刮毛啦
Guess I could get used to shaving naked at the gym.
最难受的部分是  孩子们以后不需要我们了
The hardest part is, our kids aren't gonna need us anymore.
虽然这也表示我们教育他们很成功
And it does means we raised them right.
往好的方面想
On the bright side,
他们其中一个还吸了客厅的地毯
one of them actually vacuumed the living room rug,
看起来跟...  全新的一样
and... looks brand new.
- 快帮我  -别理她  我比较需要你们
- Guys, help! - Don't listen to her! I need you more!
我在派对上打翻了饮料  然后道格...
I spilled my drink at the party, and Doug came...
蛇偷下了蛋  然后蛇蛋意外地...
and the snake laid eggs, and it accidentally
-混进了复活节彩蛋里  -闭嘴
- got mixed in with the Easter eggs... - Shut up!
妈  我知道你跟我说过别买贵的太阳眼镜
Mom, I know you told me not to buy expensive sunglasses
因为我肯定会搞丢  但是我...
because I'd only lose them, but then I...
在你头上呢
They're on your head.
那就好
Oh. Cool.
你找到了吗
Hey! You find it?
没  但是我刚才意识到
No, but I just realized
为什么人家把骰子丢了两个1叫"蛇蛋"了
why they call rolling two ones with dice "Snake eggs."
那是叫"蛇眼"
That's snake eyes.
是吗  那我刚才意识到了什么鬼啊
Oh. Then what did I realize?
别担心  我来搞定
Don't worry. I got this.
你为什么要穿兔子装
What's with the bunny suit?
我需要有个不让人起疑的理由出来院子啊
Well, I needed a plausible reason to be out in the yard.
-这是你家啊  -其实是我喜欢这变装服啦
- It's your house. - Okay, I-I like the costume.
我找到一个啦
I found one!
-糟糕  -我来
- Oh, no! - On it!
我从没看过那么多漂亮的彩蛋呢
I've never seen so many pretty ones.
妈妈
Mama!
复活节兔兔偷了我的桶子
The Easter Bunny stole my basket!
那是因为我是复活节大盗啊
T-That's because I'm the Easter Bandit.
你过去这年有点不乖
You were a little bad last year.
我知道啦
I know.
我有五个啦
I have five now!
五个彩蛋吗
Five eggs?!
那恭喜你啊
Well, congratulations!
你可以用这五颗蛋
You get to trade these five eggs
换这一个...
for one...
太阳能小径灯
solar path light!
这颗蛋在动
This egg's moving!
稍等  稍等  稍等
Wait, wait, wait!
等等等等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
那是颗魔法蛋
That is a magic egg.
闭上你的眼睛许个愿
Close your eyes and make a wish.
好了
Okay.
-我的蛋呢  -消失了  我得走啦
- Where's my egg? - Disappeared. Gotta go!
那能不能至少跟你合照一张呢
Uh, can I at least get a picture with you?
爷爷
Grandpa!
快速拍一张
One very quick pic.
抱歉  不小心手指挡住镜头了
Uhp! Got my own finger. Sorry.
拍到我自己了  怎么会这样
Well, that's me. How'd I do that?
好了
Here we go.
等等  有电话打来了
Wait. I'm getting a call.
我有认识在特拉华州的人吗
Who do I know in Delaware?
让它转语音信箱吧  吉姆
Let it go to voicemail, Jim!
好的
Okay.
别扭来扭去了  复活节兔子
Stop squirming, Easter Bunny!
一
And one...
三
Three!
-拍好了  -祝大家今年愉快
- Got it. - Have a good year, everybody!
要乖一点  尤其是你
Be good! Especially you!
到底有什么急事  艾丽克斯
What is the big emergency, Alex?
我正在用吸尘器给自己做假吻痕
I was using my Shop-Vac to give myself a hickey
要在游戏之夜跟兄弟们炫耀呢
to show the guys at game night.
你好啊  道格
Hello, Doug.
妈妈来了
Oh. The mother.
艾丽克斯不会跟你去游戏之夜了
Look, Alex isn't coming to game night.
她也不会再帮你做肋排  帮你洗衣服
She's also not cooking you ribs, doing your laundry,
以及帮你得到线上工商管理学硕士学位
or getting you an online M.B.A.
其实这件事我可能会完成它
Actually, I might finish that.
-我觉得我们会上院长嘉许名单呢  -嘘
- I really think we could make the Dean's List. - Tch!
我们有过约定
Well, we had a deal,
所以如果她不遵守约定
so if she's not gonna keep up her end,
那我就只能去告她了
I guess I'll just have to sue.
不不不  道格
Oh, no, no, no, Doug.
我觉得这件事情呢
I think that we can work that out
我们现在就能在这里摆平
right here, right now.
你觉得...
What do you think...
这个数如何
of this number?
后面如果多一个0的话我会满意许多
I'd like it a lot better with another zero on the end.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
我怪我自己
Well... I blame myself.
你  你试图灌输给孩子
You... You try to instill
要有责任心  而结果...
a sense of responsibility in your children, and...
很明显我很失败
obviously, I failed.
我真是一点都没什么好意外的
I don't know why I'm surprised.
这就是我的人生吧
It's the story of my life.
婚姻无爱  找不到工作  现在又...
Loveless marriage, no job, and now...
不知为何  我居然敢自以为
Some reason, I thought that being a mother
当母亲是我唯一做得还行的事
would be the one thing I got right.
能请你高抬贵手  等起码周三再去兑现吗
Could you at least wait till Wednesday to cash this?
不能
No.
你悲惨的人生我很遗憾
Sorry about your miserable life.
我相信你能振作起来的
I have faith that you'll get it together.
-哎哟  -妈妈
- Ohh! - Oh, Mom!
我的手腕
Oh! Oh, my wrist!
-我的手腕啊  -天啊
- My wrist! - Oh, my God.
骨折了  他推的我
It's broken! He pushed me!
-我才没有呢  -有  你就有  我看到了
- No, I didn't! - Yes! You did! I saw it.
你虐待老人
That's elder abuse.
你惹错阿嬷了
You messed with the wrong Gamma.
简单来说  道格跟我决定互不赊欠
Long story short, Doug and I decided to call it even.
而多亏有我  没有孩子被蛇咬
And, thanks to me, not one child got bit.
你真的要留下这玩意吗
Are you really gonna keep that thing?
不能有人跟我说话时不问我的蛇吗
Do we always have to talk about my snake?
这太快了
Okay, this is too soon.
她应该再过两周才生啊
She wasn't supposed to give birth for two more weeks.
就是说嘛  不是我想批评女人
Yeah, and, you know, not to be critical of women,
但是再憋一阵子才生能有多难呢
but how hard is it just to hold it in?
我可是试过喝了超大杯咖啡
You know, I had that giant coffee
然后憋著看完曼尼的独角戏《万尼亚舅舅》
and sat through Manny's one-man "Uncle Vanya."
我们...  我们还没弄好婴儿防护措施
We... We... We still haven't baby-proofed.
我们没...  没有换尿布台
We don't... We don't have a changing table.
我也还没开始画
I haven't even started
宝宝婴儿床上方的天花板壁画呢
painting the mural above the baby's crib yet.
看来早生这事也还是有一点好处的
Okay, so I guess there are some positives.
爸爸们
Guys!
莉莉  抱歉  我忘了你在后座
Lily, I'm so sorry. I forgot you're back there.
每次你说话  感觉都像是有鬼跳出来了
And every time you speak, it's like a... a ghost popping out.
后座没有幼童安全椅
There's no carseat back here.
莉莉  你不需要幼童安全椅了
Okay, Lily, you don't need a carseat.
亲爱的  别闹了  别什么事都扯到你身上
Honey, not everything is about you! Come on!
是给宝宝坐
For the baby!
我天  我的天啊
Oh. Oh, my G... Oh, my God!
它被收起来了  在搬家车上
It's packed away. It's... It's in the moving truck.
好  但能...  能请你快点吗
Okay, but can... can you hurry?
抱歉我来晚了
Sorry I was late.
有个烟鬼[警察]摆了一个补熊夹[测速]
A smokey set up a bear trap,
害我得倒退锤子[减速]
and I had to back off the hammer.
我很快就帮你把幼儿安全椅拿出来
I'll get your carseat in no time.
其他搬家工人呢
Where are the movers?
他们算什么搬家工人啊  搬箱子的男人罢了
Those were no movers. They were just men carrying boxes.
里面的东西是在我们打包前就坏了的对吧
Those things were broken before we packed them, huh?
我们刚才有把安全椅安装正确吗
Are we sure we put the carseat in right?
什么"我们"  我不知道啊  我觉得有点晃
What do you mean, we? I-I-I don't know. It felt shaky!
天啊  真糟糕  情况真的很糟糕
Oh, God, this is bad. This is really bad.
我们没有尿布  也没有奶粉
We don't have diapers, we don't have formula...
我们连自己住哪里都不知道
I don't even know where we live.
如果有人跟我们要地址  我们该说什么
If somebody asks for an address, what am I supposed to say?
住"新家那里"
"Some new house someplace"?
-两位  -要命啦
- Guys. - Ohhh, my gosh!
天啊  我们真糟糕
O-O-Oh, my God. Oh, my God. We're awful.
我们都还没关心过你
We haven't even checked in with you.
你...  你一定也吓坏了吧
You... You must be freaking out, too.
我没有  你们也没有
No, I'm not, and neither are you.
这只是你们遇到事情的流程
This is just your process.
你们会先歇斯底里
You get hysterical,
然后开始过度担心每个小细节
you worry about every detail,
然后开始互相怪罪对方
then you turn on each other...
-我们才没有呢  -我们的确是这样
- No, we don't! - Yes, we do.
-你怎么敢这么说  -在所有的发神经过去后
- How dare you. - And after all that craziness,
当真正关键的时刻来临  你们...
when it really matters the most, you...
-怎么样  -我们会怎么做
- W-What? - W-W-What do we do?
我们的儿子
Our son.
他真好看
He's beautiful.
我们能行的
We got this.
-是的  -对
- Yeah. - Yeah.
好  歌洛莉亚说
Okay, so, Gloria said
她把乔以前的摇篮放在我们卧室了
she set up Joe's old bassinet in our bedroom,
我们也有足够的尿布够撑到早上
and I think we have enough diapers to last us till morning.
别忘了撑著他的脑袋
D-Don't forget to support his head.
我知道  又不是第一次
I will. It's not my first rodeo.
我等不及带他第一次去看牛仔表演了
Oh, I can't wait to take him to his first rodeo.
好  她在问我们应该什么时间
Okay, um, she's asking what time
带大家来跟宝宝见第一面
she should bring everyone by for the baby reveal.
我不知道  或许...
I don't know, may...
或许今晚我们先四个人自己过吧
Maybe it should just be the four of us tonight, huh?
我想...  我终于知道
You know, I... think I finally realized
这房子一直以来缺的是什么了
what this house has been missing all along.
-嵌入式灯具  -没错
- Recessed lighting. - Totally.